

## **DIRECTOR & DESIGNER OF USER EXPERIENCE**

Talented manager of user-experience design with the proven know-how to combine creative and usability viewpoints resulting in successful Web and mobile applications. Over eight years of success optimizing user engagement for small business and large corperation. Expert in providing compelling user experiences to improve brand loyalty, customer retention and visit-to-order ratios.

#### **UX SKILLS**

Collaboration, Competitive evaluation, Concept modeling, Contextual inquiry, Diagramming, Ethnography, Facilitation, Graphic facilitation, Heuristic evaluation, High fidelity prototyping, Interviewing, Personas, Scenarios, Sitemaps, Sketching, Specifications, Strategy Development, Surveying, Task Flows, Team-building, Usability testing, Wireframes, Workshops

#### **DESIGNER TOOLBOX**

UX & UI Design, Usability Protocols, Web Site Analytics, Prototyping, Persona Creation, Information Architecture (IA), A/B, Card Sort, User Testing, Animation/Motion Graphics, Affinity Diagramming, Requirements Definition, HTML/XHTML, CSS2/CSS3, JavaScript/jQuery, Flash/Fireworks, Photoshop/Sketch

#### **PROGRAM KNOWLEDGE**

## **Project Management**

Basecamp, Highrise, Asana, Zoho, SharePoint, Salesforce

#### **UX/UI** Design

Sketch, Invisionapp, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign

#### Web

MySQL, CSS3, HTML5, SASS, jQuery, Wordpress, Drupal, Joomla, Hubspot, Optimizely, Wistia

#### Media

Final Cut Pro, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Encore, Cinema 4D

#### Communication

Skype, Slack, GoToMeeting, Join.Me



## **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance UI/UX Designer & Front-end Developer

Kahl Payne | Sacramento, CA | April 2010-present

As a career driven self-taught Web/UI Designer with a big passion to Code, I build partnerships and create intuitive and easy to use products for a variety of clients. Projects range from UX/UI design consulting, project management, media strategy development, SEM campaigning, website design, front-end development and graphic design (print & digital). Clients range from VC startup companies to small business entrepreneurs.

I work directly with clients, translating business goals and objectives into compelling design solutions. I manage a high volume of campaign-oriented projects for retainer clients. I'm entirely responsible for the visual design and front-end technologies to deliver a quality user experience.

My role as UX Design Lead requires me to wear many hats including project manager, copy writer, information architect and client counselor. For most projects, I'm expected to deliver wireframes, sitemaps, visual design mockups, and HTML prototypes, while adhering to aggressive project timelines. I am also heavily involved in CMS integration and deploying front-end code into our .NET framework.

#### Contract UI/UX Designer & Video Producer

Emtrain | Sacramento, CA | June 2014-present

In my role as a UI/UX Developer at Emtrain I lead research, design strategy, interaction design and visual design for their main website and client LMS (Learning Management Tool). As a member of the UX Team, I enjoyed working with a number of great clients including Under Armour, Netflix, Western Digital & Safeway. My process has involved foundational research into user personas and a high-level strategy, collaboration on branding and 'look and feel,' heavy sketching, wire-framing and prototyping, visual design, and collaboration with developers on the little details that matter.

I was responsible for the interaction, usability, information architecture and visual design. In addition to my day-to-day tasks of design creation, I also led the User Experience team, monitoring workloads and providing creative direction for all projects. As a leader within our Product Management team, my efforts were split between product strategy, visioning, mentoring and tactical implementation.



## **UX** Improvements:

- Increased collaboration and communication between the design, development, and marketing leadership teams.
- Implemented formal design reviews, created best practices around documentation and specification, encouraged the team to do more prototyping, and insisted on whiteboard usage while talking through problems.
- Created concept models, reviews, sitemaps, process flows, sketches, wireframes, prototypes, and detailed specifications for mobile/tablet.
- Worked closely with visual, copy, production and programming team members to create intuitive, delightful user experiences.
- · Managed the use of A/B split testing, managing signup forms and increasing member accounts.
- Crafted user-experience design into major areas of the website and LMS tool, increasing user engagement.

### Contract UI/UX Designer

Hitbridge | Elk Grove, CA | June 2012-present

As a part-time consultant for this start-up, I lead UX development and design on multiple responsive website projects, while helping implement a user-centered design methodology. Collaborate closely on product planning and execution with key stakeholders to produce intuitive, delightful user experiences.

As a member of the User Experience Team, I worked directly with project managers to improve the user experience for a variety of small business websites. I developed wireframes, mockups and high-fidelity prototypes to aid testing, development and release of web-based or desktop applications.

## **UI/UX Project Manager**

i-Tul Design & Software | Roseville, CA | October 2012-July 2014

I lead the design & development team at the start-up i-Tul that provided creative media solutions for clients throughout the nation

#### Team collaboration and transparency:

One of my larger goals was to increase collaboration and communication between the design, development, and business leadership teams. I implemented formal design reviews, created best practices around documentation and specification and encouraged more prototyping while talking through problems. This helps to keep conversations on track and gets everyone on the same page.



#### Planning:

I spent a lot of time managing product and team intricacies. I helped manage the design team's workflow and timelines, and assisted with planning small and large product improvements and releases. Timelines and milestone completions were reflected in client email/phone call conversations in order to maximize workflow and efficiency for all projects.

## **UI Designer & Project Manager**

Lojo Group | Rocklin, CA | November 2010-September 2012

### Interaction Design:

Created concept models, heuristic reviews, sitemaps, process flows, sketches, wireframes, prototypes, and detailed specifications for mobile/tablet and social applications.

#### User Research:

Conducted both remote & in-person user interviews and usability tests. Created click-through and prototypes for web and mobile/tablet for use during tests. Synthesized and compiled findings to inform UX strategy.

## Collaboration:

Worked closely with visual, copy, production and programming team members to create intuitive, delightful user experiences. Loved every minute of it.

# **Contract Graphic Designer**

Clear Channel Outdoor | Sacramento, CA | April 2009 - June 2014

Collaborated with sales team with creative campaigns to develop and design successful outdoor marketing billboards around the Sacramento region.

## **Graphic Designer & Video Editor**

CBS13 | Sacramento, CA | March 2009 - August 2010

Created competitive digital graphic designs for news telecast. Worked directly with producers and a team of designers to complete packages for evening news broadcast reports.timelines, and assisted with planning small and large product improvements and releases. Timelines and milestone completions were reflected in client email/phone call conversations in order to maximize workflow and efficiency for all projects.



#### **EDUCATION**

California State University, Long Beach
Bachelor of Science (BS), Business Marketing | 2004-2008

Student Organizations:

CSULB Delta Chi Fraternity

CSULB American Marketing Association (AMA)

CSULB International Business Association (IBA)

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.